You'll wish it was only make-believe.
Child's Play is a horror film directed by Tom Holland.
After being shot in a toy store, a serial killer
transfers his soul into a Good Guy doll.
A mother then gifts it to her 6-year old son Andy,
which unleashes terror upon the city.
Andy Barclay, played by Alex Vincent.
Chucky (voice) / Charles Lee Ray, played by Brad Dourif.
Karen Barclay, played by Catherine Hicks.
Mike Norris, played by Chris Sarandon.
Maggie Peterson, played by Dinah Manoff.
Jack Santos, played by Tommy Swerdlow.
Child's Play is a 1988 American supernatural slasher film directed by Tom Holland, from a
screenplay he co-wrote with Don Mancini and John Lafia based on a story by Mancini.
The film stars Catherine Hicks and Chris Sarandon with
Brad Dourif as the voice of Chucky.
Its plot follows a widowed mother who gives a new doll to her son,
unaware that it is possessed by the soul of a serial killer.
Child's Play was released in the United States on
November 9, 1988, by MGM/UA Communications Co.
through its United Artists label.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed more than
$44 million against a production budget of $9 million.
Along with the film gaining a cult following, the box office success also spawned a media franchise that includes a
series of six sequels, a television series, merchandise, novels, comic books, a video game, and a reboot.
The original Child's Play film was distributed by United Artists, although the
rights to the series were sold to Universal Pictures in 1990.
MGM (via United Artists) retained the rights to the original film and Orion Pictures
(through United Artists Releasing) also distributed the reboot in 2019.
A sequel, Child's Play 2, was released in 1990.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, birthday, gun, voodoo, stalker.
The tone is dark.